Sister|
Sister.
Why are you so late?
Something happened.
What's the rush?
Just say it.
Fang just called
and said someone died at Xinmai Hotel.
The chief assigned this case to us.
Shao is already on his way.
Captain Zhuang,
are we going to the scene?
Can I go this time?
Take good care of yourself.
Then yes.
Name and birthplace.
Is everyone here?
Where is Cheng Mo?
He was just here.
Forget about him.
Mia,
what's wrong with your face?
You two have been with Shao for so long.
And you're still throwing up like this?
Fang.
Take a few more photos.
You'd better put this on.
It really smells in here.
With the body decomposed to this extent,
the time of death is at least ten days ago.
Lin.
It's not that we're cowards.
Just put it on.
No need.
It's a piece of cake.
According to the hotel's registration info,
the deceased is Li Ting.
Male, 37.
I've already checked.
He was a writer.
Look,
here are surveillance photos from the hotel.
Notify Shao
to do a DNA identification on the body.
Lin, I told you.
Shao is here.
Shao.
I collected them long ago.
I was about to head back.
Look.
Have you found the cause of death?
So far,
we only found one trauma on the back of his head.
There are no obvious signs of a struggle.
And before he died,
there were clear attempts to save himself.
Judging from the bloody handprints on the bathtub,
at least twice.
So I think...
He accidentally slipped when getting out of the bathtub,
causing traumatic brain injury,
and died of massive hemorrhage.
When did you get here?
Just now.
He's always so elusive.
Ignore him.
Go on.
According to the preliminary investigation,
homicide is ruled out.
Who reported it first?
A cleaning lady named Liu Ying.
Where is she?
She was scared to death. She's calming down outside.
Radiating your humanity again.
Wow.
He's really a talent.
No.
Isn't he hemophobic?
The blood has dried, it's fine.
Xiaobai.
Are you done throwing up?
If you are fine, help me take some notes.
Okay.
This young man,
it's a pity he's not a forensic doctor.
Let's go.
Watch for a while longer.
Hello, Officer.
Hello. What's your name?
Dong Shan.
Hello. I'd like to ask you some questions.
How long had the deceased lived here?
He was already here when I moved in.
I'm not quite sure.
Do you have any strong impressions of him?
Strong impressions?
Oh.
He had a big beard,
was chubby,
wore glasses,
and liked to wear a top hat.
He was about this tall.
Is this
the only door you have here?
There's another one in the back.
There's a back door?
Did you notice if he usually interacted with anyone?
Did anyone ever come looking for him?
He rarely interacted with people.
He didn't go out much either.
Except for
couriers or delivery guys dropping things off.
Okay.
Ma'am,
I've brought him here.
Hello, Officer.
I'm the lobby manager of Xinmai Hotel.
The deceased, Li Ting.
Did you know him before?
Of course I do.
He is a long-term guest of our hotel,
but he had a bit of a bad temper.
He's been dead for so long.
How come no one noticed?
Don't you usually clean the rooms?
That was his own request.
He said without his permission,
we are not allowed to enter the room to clean.
If he doesn't let you clean, you don't go?
Well,
you really can't blame us.
Who would dare to ask for trouble?
Before,
he stayed in his room alone for a week.
We were also worried about his safety,
so we went in to take a look under the pretext of cleaning.
But he kicked us out immediately.
Manager,
didn't he tell us not to knock?
It's fine.
Mr. Li,
hello.
You haven't left your room for a week.
We're here to clean your room.
Is it convenient?
Are you there?
What is it?
Oh,
room service here to change your towels.
When did I call for room service?
Mr. Li, you misunderstood.
Our hotel must ensure
the safety of our guests.
You haven't left your room for a week.
We were worried about you.
What are you worried about?
Are you worried I'd die inside?
No.
Your hotel is really something.
I told the front desk
not to disturb me without my permission.
Yes.
If you keep disturbing me like this,
how can I create?
Sorry, sorry.
Go.
I'm sorry.
Then have a good rest.
Give me a bottle of water.
Towel.
Sorry.
Have a good rest.
Do you remember when it was?
May 5th.
You remember it so clearly.
It was our first time getting scolded for worrying about a guest.
How could I not remember?
But he left the next day,
and didn't return until half a month ago.
During this time,
aside from asking us to clean his room before he left,
we never entered without permission.
Our hotel
highly respects the personal privacy of our guests.
Xiaobai,
verify this.
Yes, ma'am.
He rarely interacted with others.
Lao Fang,
I'm here.
Okay, thank you.
Go ahead with your work. I'll contact you if anything comes up.
Okay, officer.
I'm here, Captain Zhuang.
Go and copy the surveillance footage as well.
Okay.
Okay, come with me.
Yeah, sorry to bother you.
Mr. Cheng.
We still need to collect evidence.
You'll ruin the scene like this.
Sir.
Sir,
please come out.
You can't be in here.
Sir.
Sir,
you can't touch this.
Mr. Cheng, please don't.
Put it down.
I'm looking for evidence.
Oh.
I could call you stupid,
but your usual logical analysis skills are quite strong.
But if I call you smart,
you don't know how to be flexible at a time like this.
This room has the exact same layout as room 208.
If you really want to analyze something, do it here.
Why do you have to go over there and cause trouble?
Thank you.
You actually know how to say thank you?
I wasn't good with words before.
You can use your divergent thinking now.
Whatever you were thinking about just now,
you can finish it here.
Really.
Stop.
When someone is taking a shower,
why would they pull the curtain?
Even if he is someone who enjoys his private space,
he would pull the curtain all the way.
Do you remember at the crime scene,
where this curtain was pulled to?
I remember.
He pulled it to here.
Stop.
While showering,
people usually face the faucet
because it's easier to reach things.
But the gap in the curtain was facing the bed.
That means
there is something extremely important over there.
But the door was locked from the inside at the time.
What important thing did he have
that he had to keep staring at?
Or maybe something
with a mind of its own?
Perhaps a person.
That makes sense.
In that instant,
the accident happened.
He slipped
and hit the back of his head.
Stop.
If he slipped and wanted to push himself up,
he should have used his entire palm.
But now,
he was using his five fingertips.
That means what he was trying to grab was
someone who left him to die or took the chance to kill him.
That person must have had a grudge against him.
Good analysis, young man.
The self-cultivation of a police officer.
As expected,
it's not as simple as an accidental death.
Check the surveillance cameras outside carefully.
There should be new discoveries.